heartland.org 2011-06-10

# The Heartland Institute: Privacy Policy

The Heartland Institute is firmly committed to protecting the privacy of its Web site visitors. This privacy policy statement describes our information-gathering and dissemination practices for:

  * www.heartland.org
  * www.globalwarmingheartland.org
  * www.heartlandstore.org (an Amazon Webstore also governed by [its privacy policy](http://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496))
  * www.chcchoices.org
  * www.nipccreport.org
  * www.newcoalition.org
  * www.budgetandtax-news.org
  * www.environmentandclimate-news.org
  * www.healthpolicy-news.org
  * www.infotech-news.org
  * www.schoolreform-news.org

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests. We will not sell, reveal, or share your personal information.

Our sites’ registration forms require users to give us contact information (names and email addresses, for example). The user’s contact information is used to contact the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.

Our sites contain links to other sites. The Heartland Institute is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such Web sites.

Our sites use order forms for users to request information, products, and services. We collect visitor’s financial information (account or credit card numbers, for example) and contact information (email addresses, for example). Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services. Contact information that is collected is used to fulfill orders and send information about our organization to our users. The user’s contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.

Our online surveys sometimes ask visitors for demographic information (zip code, age, or income level, for example). We use this data to tailor our visitor’s experience at our sites, showing them content we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences.

We run contests on our site in which we ask visitors for contact information (like email addresses) and demographic information (zip code, age, or income level, for example). We use contact data from our contests to send information about our organization to our visitors. The user’s contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.

 **Security**

The Heartland Institute’s Web sites have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of information under our control.

 **Choice/Opt-Out**

Our print and email publications and communications provide users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us.

At any time, users can ask to be removed from our print and email lists. Our email communications contain an auto-unsubscribe option, or a request can be sent to [database@heartland.org](mailto:database@heartland.org). We ask that such requests specify whether the user wishes to be removed from all email communications or only those pertaining to specific products the user is receiving. The Heartland Institute promptly responds to all unsubscribe requests.

 **Contacting Online Services**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of these sites, or your interaction with them, please contact:

Diane Bast  
Executive Editor  
The Heartland Institute  
19 South LaSalle Street #903  
Chicago, IL 60603
